The divide over how to use Bitcoin and Blockchain
is really a part of much broader debate
that our society are having right now  about open vs closed systems
with virtual currency in a blockchain
original believers in this technology
I think a lot of people in Sillicon Valley
still have this idea that most important part of the system is that it's open
that anybody can use it and anybody can participate
just like wikipedia that anybody can comment and edit entries
and add their expertise and knowledge to the system.
I think Wall Street and government
There is a suspition of sort-of open systen that Bitcoin
and Ethereum represents where anybody can participate
In order to maintain the security of the system
on Wall Street and government
There is a desire to have a sort-of limited number of people, participating
you can essentially know that you can trust every body in the system
TRUST DISRUPTED
BITCOIN AND THE BLOCKCHAIN
TechCrunch Originals
6. Co-opt vs Disrupt
$37 Billion : Goldman Sachs estimate of the potential annual benefits of blockchain technology
$37 Billion : Goldman
Sachs estimate of the
potential annual benefits of blockchain technology 100 : Percent
of the 10 largest global banks partering with R3 consortium
R3 is currently building a system , private system
It does seem to me that you get much benefit from closed ledger, private ledger
sure there is some benefit.What is really different
between a private ledger built on blockchain technology and a private ledge built on sql database technology
major financial institutions are skeptical about open ledgers for a set of reasons
First of all , Wall street operates under a set of  regulatory constrains
that they cannot afford to just ignore
Their central bankers or  their various different securitie or derivative regulators. Their conduct regulators
I have a front seat to the question about can bitcoin technology and blockchain technology work in regulated environement
because I am on a board of the company Coinbase which is
probably the leading exchange and hosted wallet provider here in United States
one of the leading company around the world
And they have to operate in a regulated environment
if you look at the Bitcoin debate  right now
where they are arguing over  the block size
and they are having a trouble scaling that system
and they are only at a  point of now where they can  handle 7 transactions a second
and The world global finance handles thousands if not tens of thousands
, hundreds of thousands of transactions every second
if you includes  credit card swipes and trades and securities etc,etc.
I am not yet convinced the  private block chain is anything new
It's probably a tool to help  information sharing  between Banks
But then , if you consider the infomation sharing has to be associated with common codes of business practise.
then you also have to consider that it is a  route towards cartelization of the   banking sector
and in worse case scenario , it creates one bank system
at a high leve, I just kind-of  think it is  an industry  grapling with a new technology  not really liking what they see
Sillion Valley vision used to be ** evolving.
is one in which future of money